MANSI SHARMA

PROFESSIONAL SUMMARY

Legal professional consistently able to take initiative and persevere in routine complex cases. Analytical in approaching legal questions and developing solid solutions based on precedents. Critical thinker with analytical mindset and good public speaking skills. Manages complex cases and produces results to tight deadlines. Outstanding at document control, negotiation and deep-dive research.

EXPERIENCE

Legal Officer, 09/2021 - Current SHRIRAM GENERAL INSURANCE COMPANY - Jaipur, India

- In SGIC core dealing in MACT Claims (High Value Claims above 20 Lacs) & Arbitration.
- And looking after 5 states i.e. Gujarat, Uttarakhand, Bihar, Jharkhand and Daman and Diu.
- Here, working majorly in Motor Vehicle Act i.e. Road Accidents and in which we receive death claims/Compensation and defend/contest the case of the Insurance Company.
- Moreover, attending proceedings in MACT Tribunals, drafting, Police Interactions, Investigations in the Fraud Claims.
- Compliance and Criminal Litigation.
- Presented complex arguments relating to defence cases contesting the in front of courts, tribunals and committees.
- Advised clients on legislation and case law change affecting their case.
- Advocated for clients in their absence on preliminary matters, representing clients views and opinions accurately.

Legal Associate, 03/2021 - 07/2021 KEDIA CORPORATES AND ADVISORS - Jaipur, India

- In Kedia Corporates dealing was in RERA Tribunal basically dealing in Real Estate and in the same it was moreover drafting as in Land Agreements, Power of Attorney, Rent Agreements.
- Further, there was tribunal visits Client dealing field work as in Project visits.
- And Labour Law related work too.
- Reviewed and analysed litigation files to brief colleagues and clients.
- Worked to tight deadlines on real estate cases to meet client needs and maintain high levels of effective and efficient case management.
- Gave advice to clients at conclusion of matters regarding firm's policies including retention and destruction of papers.



CONTACT

Address: JAIPUR 302020 **Phone:** +916378737461,

Email: sharma.mansi1739@gmail.com

CORE QUALIFICATIONS

- Legal Research
- Leadership
- Teamwork
- Problem Solving
- Filing
- Project Management

- Undertook research and analysis on documents and case law to guarantee accurate guidance and methods.
- Verified paperwork to check for authenticity before signing and implementing.

Legal Associate, 08/2020 - 02/2021 KASLIWAL CHAMBERS AND ASSOCIATES - Jaipur, India

- As a Legal Associate working in DRT matters and assisting in Civil and Criminal matters too.
- Drafting petition, writs and Applications and Cheque Bounce.
- Reviewed and analysed litigation files to brief colleagues and clients.
- Worked to tight deadlines on civil cases to meet client needs and maintain high levels of effective and efficient case management.
- Responded to inquiries, delivered general legal advice and determined next steps for cases.
- Handled caseloads, developing client loyalty through the competent management and completion of projects in line with client needs.

EDUCATION

LLM, Corporate Law, 2022 NIMS UNIVERSITY - Jaipur, RJ

BA.LLB, 2020

MODY UNIVERSITY - Jaipur, RJ

CERTIFICATIONS

Spanish Language Diploma and Certification

ADDITIONAL INFORMATION

Internship and Training:

• Training on: High Court Advocate

Organization: High Court

Brief: Criminal Lawyer (Mr. A.K. Gupta)

• Training on: Rajasthan State Commission for Women, Jaipur

Organization: Women commission Brief: Family Law (Mrs. Suman Sharma)

• Training on: Singhi and Singhi Law Chambers

Organization: Corporate Law firm, Jaipur

Brief: Civil and Company Law (Mr. Anuroop Singh)

• Training on: District and Session Court

Organisation: District and Session Court, Jaipur

Brief: Miscellaneous Civil and Criminal (Mr. Alok Sharma)